[narrator]
We are no different from the Ants.
No… we are far worse.
[dramatic music playing]
[glass clinks]
In survivors' bodies,
the poison was absorbed,
eating them away from the inside.
The rapid destruction of
their organs began soon after,
In other words…
[opening theme music playing]
[singer singing in Japanese]
[singer singing in English]
THE WORD X IS X YOU
[whooshing]
[splashes echo]
And if you have, then we must evacuate.
Very well.
All that's left to do
is for me to locate and capture
all of the remaining intruders.
Your secret intrigues me and
I intend to know it soon enough.
I will keep my word, sire,
even if it costs me my life.
I can see all that has changed
since the first time I used En.
Footprints that weren't there before.
An abandoned vehicle.
Youpi's corpse.
A door that's been opened.
And someone new who reacts to my En!
Someone has killed Youpi, was it you?
[gasps]
No, sire! Absolutely not.
I am just a lowly Squadron Leader!
I respected Sir Youpi
and I had no reason to kill him!
doubled over in pain, then he died.
But then, before he could
even answer my question…
before my black centipedes
even had a chance to hatch,
he was dead.
[grunts]
The Royal Guard Pouf. Oh, he's trouble.
Simply asking him to keep quiet
would be too lenient.
I should eliminate him immediately!
I should accuse him of disloyalty
and execute him.
In any case,
I must get him away from the King.
Lord Meruem, Welfin is--
[Meruem] I already know
what you're about to say.
[gasps]
I can now sense the emotions
of everyone who my En has touched,
[Shaiapouf] So it wasn't just
Youpi's wings and attacks,
the King also inherited
my Spiritual Message.
Not only that, but it seems
he's made it infinitely more powerful.
[gasps]
Sire!
The King is invincible!
The King is unrivaled!
And yet…
[heart beating]
Why?!
What is this feeling washing over me?
Why is my heart filled with such
overwhelming anxiety?
but there is no hiding the raw malice
that you feel for me.
It surges even now.
Your hatred is undeniable, and I am quite
interested to learn what drives it.
[Shaiapouf] This is no time
to let emotion best me!
[dramatic music playing]
He is deeply involved in my secret.
However, he has not yet realized this.
Huh? Huh?
[Shaiapouf] You may continue to question
him if you wish, sire.
When the King has such power,
lies are futile.
I must rely on the truth!
Although I am certain
you wish to receive your reward,
I can use the truth to muddle the facts.
Secret? What secret?
Damn it! I didn't realize
he was this powerful!
I should have run away right off the bat.
Ah! Temptation got the better of me!
When I saw how Youpi had shrunken
from a giant down to the size of a bug,
then dropped dead,
I started thinking I might be
strong enough to take down the King.
Oh, but that was just a delusion.
That's why I stayed.
I felt alive.
In all the chaos that happened,
I remembered Gyro,
But he isn't even dead.
Gyro is alive, he has to be!
I should have run off
and teamed up with him again,
then we could have sought revenge!
Damn it!
It's all that octopus' fault.
That little bastard threw me off my game.
He messed with my emotions.
I let him lead me astray!
[groans] "Messenger," my ass!
He'll send my head flying
before I can even activate Missileman!
Think. What tools do I have left?
The message? Pouf's secret?
The root of my hatred?
Whatever it is,
the first word out of my mouth
will be crucial.
Just one word will decide
whether I live or die.
If I choose the wrong one, it's all over!
[Welfin gasps]
Think carefully before you answer.
That will have consequences.
I must presume that you are prepared
for them.
[Shaiapouf gasping]
I want a sincere answer.
[Shaiapouf] This is…
[narrator] The King's new power
meant he had access to the answer.
Although he understood that
he had Pouf's absolute devotion,
each of these factors were equally
meaningless in the eyes of the King.
[dramatic music playing]
[Shaiapouf] Even then…
I was prepared.
I already knew that I was going to die.
to my own loyalty.
We are in the midst of our match.
[narrator] His resolve
was nothing short of incredible.
stopped the King in his tracks.
[screams]
…Welfin understood immediately.
[Welfin] This is it.
[Welfin] I'm dead.
[narrator] Sensing his own fate,
Welfin began to age, and within moments,
it was as if a hundred years had passed.
[Welfin] I want to live.
[narrator] In his mind, Welfin's entire
life passed by him in a jumbled flash,
[narrator] Caught between the desire
to live and unavoidable death…
Pouf's secret!
One word!
I won't die.
Don't die until you're dead!
[narrator] His brain worked feverishly
as it never had before
and selected a word that,
under normal conditions,
never would have occurred to him.
[imperceptible]
[Shaiapouf] This…
This is how intensely he cares for her.
So this is your secret.
[Shaiapouf] Yes.
I will accept any punishment.
[Meruem] You know what it shall be.
I do not have to speak it.
You and I are of one mind.
I do not blame you.
[Shaiapouf] I never had a chance.
Yes.
[Meruem] Continue searching for Pitou.
The two captured intruders
may know something.
Once you are done, let them go.
[Shaiapouf] All I can do is nod in assent.
Sire.
Welfin…
But how did you know that?
[Meruem] I have come to believe
that you took on the task
at the behest of the octopus.
But I am unsure
why you failed to carry it out.
Is it connected to your deep and
sudden hatred of me, by any chance?
[gasps]
[Meruem] Ah, yes.
Now, please be at ease.
Just answer my question, and
you are free to go wherever you wish.
You have my thanks.
It's because of you that I remembered
something important.
[groans]
you're enemies!
Do you hear me?
[Meruem] Is that so?
[panting]
I hope you see him. I truly do.
And if possible…
go live a human life.
[Shaiapouf wails]
[upbeat music playing]
[Gon] Next time,
"This Person And This Moment."
[singer singing in Japanese]